In the heart of suburbia, a hit man with heart has just moved in.
The Whole Nine Yards is a comedy, crime film directed by Jonathan Lynn.
After a mobster agrees to cooperate with an FBI investigation in order to stay out of prison, he's relocated
by the authorities to a life of suburban anonymity as part of a witness protection program.
It's not long before a couple of his new neighbours figure out his true identity and
come knocking to see if he'd be up for one more hit—suburban style.
Nicholas 'Oz' Oseransky, played by Matthew Perry.
Jimmy 'Tulipán' Tudeski, played by Bruce Willis.
Cynthia Tudeski, played by Natasha Henstridge.
Jill St. Claire, played by Amanda Peet.
Franklin 'Frankie Figs' Figueroa, played by Michael Clarke Duncan.
Sophie Oseransky, played by Rosanna Arquette.
The Whole Nine Yards is a 2000 American crime
comedy film directed by Jonathan Lynn.
It was written by Mitchell Kapner and stars Bruce Willis, Matthew Perry,
Amanda Peet, Michael Clarke Duncan, and Natasha Henstridge.
The story follows a mild-mannered dentist as he travels to Chicago to inform a mob boss about
the whereabouts of his new neighbor, a former hitman with a price on his head.
The film was produced by Franchise Pictures, Rational Packaging and Lansdown Films
and was distributed by Morgan Creek Productions through Warner Bros.
It was released on February 18, 2000.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $106 million.
A sequel, The Whole Ten Yards, was released in 2004.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois,
gangster, montreal, canada, mafia, dentist.
The tone is lighthearted.